Cynthia Uleman Collection 176
DCPL Special Collections - MLK Library
Cynthia Uleman Collection
1975-2012
DCPL Special Collections - MLK Library
Uleman, Cynthia
176
3.5 Linear feet
5 Boxes
Arrangement
Series 1: Correspondence, .25 linear feet, (1980-1990) This series includes letters sent to Cynthia Uleman by friends and acquaintances. Some of the letters are on the back of poster fliers. Series 2: Fliers, .25 linear feet, (1980-1990 and undated) This series contains fliers for concerts and special events, including a benefit for Jello Biafra's legal defense, a benefit for the D.C. Rape Crisis Center, and a protest against apartheid at the South African Embassy, mostly in the D.C. area. Arranged alphabetically by venue name. Series 3: Mail Art, .5 linear feet, (1980-1990 and undated) This series includes envelope and postcard mail art. Arranged in original order. Series 4: Publications, 0.25 linear feet, (19880-1990 and undated) This series includes a copy of The Abolition of Work and Other Essays, by Bob Black, published by Loompanics Unlimited, Port Townsend, Washington. Series 5: Zines, 1.5 linear feet (1980-1990 and undated) This series includes zines created mostly in the United States, and miscellaneous pages from unidentified zines. Arranged alphabetically by title.
Biographical / Historical
Cynthia Uleman was born on January 20, 1945 and grew up in Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania listening to rock music. As a student at the University of Wisconsin, she became interested in bluegrass and folk music. After three years in Washington state, she moved to the Washington, D.C. area with her family, and in 1971 settled in the Takoma Park neighborhood, in Maryland. She began patronizing D.C. area record stores including Joe's Record Paradise, Vinyl Ink, and Phantasmagoria. She also listened to WMUC, a college radio station at the University of Maryland, particularly enjoying the weekly Tom Lyle Show, which featured punk bands, and advertised punk concerts in the D.C. area. Uleman attended concerts all over the region, where she began collecting zines and related materials. Between 1984 and 1987, Uleman and Michael Voo Doo (a pen name) began exchanging mail art, including particular subjects of American culture: cows, clowns, cowboys, and rodeos. Uleman and Michael Voo Doo never met, and she eventually lost contact with him after he moved from northern Virginia, to Florida. In 2019 Uleman was residing in Takoma Park, Maryland.
Custodial History
The collection was donated by Cynthia Uleman, 2014 and 2018.
Related Materials
Internal collections include those from the D.C.PL Punk Archive: Cynthia Connolly Collection No. 170 John Davis Collection No. 175 Eddie Janney Collection No. 181 Rachel Sengers Collection No. 173 Related external collections include the Punk and Indie Fanzine Collection at the University of Maryland, College Park. https://archives.lib.umd.edu/repositories/4/resources/411 Collection 0195-SCPA
Scope and Contents
The collection contains fliers for musical performances, mail art, correspondence, publications, and zines Cnythia Uleman collected throughout the 1970s and 1980s.
Ephemera; Correspondence; Zines; Music; Punk rock music
- Series 1: Correspondence, 1980-1990; 0.25 Linear Feet
- Series 2: Fliers, 1980-1990; 0.25 Linear Feet
  - 715 Club (Box 1)
    - Graveyards from Outer Space (Box 1)
  - Black Cat (Box 1)
    - Maximum Summer: The Bepstein Documentary (Box 1)
    - The Bepstein Show (Box 1)
  - Bowie High School (Box 1)
    - Lynch, 1986-07-12 (Box 1)
  - Bunches Cafe (Box 1)
    - The Lowly Cows (Box 1)
    - The Deans (Box 1)
    - Crippled Hippo (Box 1)
  - Complex (Box 1)
    - Naked Raygun (Box 1)
    - Marginal Man (Box 1)
    - 1/2 Japanese (Box 1)
    - The Forgotten (Box 1)
  - The Complex (Box 1)
    - The Freeze (Box 1)
    - Soulside (Box 1)
    - Carpe Diem (Box 1)
    - Brendan, Eddie, Guy & Mike (Box 1)
  - d.c. space (Box 1)
    - Candybar Second Coming (Box 1)
  - Hole in the Sky (Box 1)
    - Rocky Horror Picture Show (Box 1)
  - Kelly's (Box 1)
    - Government Issue (Box 1)
    - Absence of Malice (Box 1)
    - Unseen Forces (Box 1)
  - Kilimanjaro (Box 1)
    - The Last Poets (Box 1)
    - James Blood Ulmer (Box 1)
    - HR (Box 1)
  - Lake Braddock Community Center (Box 1)
    - YAUO Benefit: The Roadside Pet (Box 1)
    - Mission Impossible (Box 1)
    - United Mutation (Box 1)
    - Lunch Meat (Box 1)
  - Astoria Theatre; The Odor; Brixton Academy; Venue; Happy Jax (Box 1)
    - U.K. Subs (Box 1)
    - 999 the Lurkers (Box 1)
    - The Vibrators (Box 1)
    - Chelsea (Box 1)
    - Chumbawamba (Box 1)
    - The 25 of May (Box 1)
    - Credit to The Nation (Box 1)
    - DJs Sonic Pollution (Box 1)
    - Master (Box 1)
    - My Dying Bride (Box 1)
    - Impaler (Box 1)
    - Headcleaner (Box 1)
    - Scissormen (Box 1)
    - Bad Religion (Box 1)
    - Fugazi (Box 1)
    - Agnostic Front (Box 1)
    - The Orb (Box 1)
    - Back to The Planet (Box 1)
  - Lupo's (Box 1)
    - !Agression! (Box 1)
    - Positive Outlook (Box 1)
    - Direct Action (Box 1)
    - Stupid Question (Box 1)
  - Northminster Presbyterian Church (Box 1)
    - D.C. Commission for Women: Ward Four Community Forum, 1987 (Box 1)
  - Rock Theatre (Box 1)
    - Descendents (Box 1)
  - St. Stephen's and the Incarnation Episcopal Church (Box 1)
    - D.C. Zine Fest, 2012-07-28 (Box 1)
    - D.C. Zine Fest, 2013-07-20 (Box 1)
  - South African Embassy (Box 1)
    - Punk Percussion Protest (Box 1)
  - Victoria Embankment; Hyde Park, 1987-03-25 (Box 1)
    - March for a Nuclear Free Britain (Box 1)
  - WUST Radio Music Hall (Box 1)
    - D.O.A., 1985-08-31 (Box 1)
    - Government Issue, 1985-08-31 (Box 1)
    - Dag Nasty, 1985-08-31 (Box 1)
    - Dead Kennedys (Box 1)
    - Government Issue (Box 1)
    - Morally Bankrupt (Box 1)
    - Cereal Killer (Box 1)
    - T.S.O.L. (Box 1)
    - Government Issue (Box 1)
    - Naked Raygun (Box 1)
    - Government Issue (Box 1)
    - T.S.O.L. (Box 1)
    - Naked Raygun (Box 1)
    - Cereal Killer (Box 1)
  - Pierce Hall (Box 5)
    - Hardcore 84, 1984 (Box 5)
- Series 3: Mail art, 1980-1990; 0.5 Linear Feet
  - Item 1, 1985 (Box 1)
  - Item 2, 1985 (Box 1)
  - Item 3, 1985 (Box 1)
  - Item 4, 1985 (Box 5)
- Series 4: Publications, 1988-1990; 0.25 Linear Feet
  - Washington Tribune, v 6, Number 19, 1982-10-08-1982-10-21 (Box 5)
  - "Abolition of Work" by Bob Black (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
- Series 5: Zines, 1980-1990; 1.5 Linear Feet
  - Sub-Series 1: D.C. Area
    - Amoeba Man, Number 1, 1985 (Box 1)
    - Artwash, v. 1, Number 2, 1975 (Box 1)
    - Binary Load Lifter (Box 1)
    - Binary Load Lifter (Box 1)
    - Chow Chow Times, Number 1, 1985 (Box 1)
    - Crawl or Die, Number 1, 1985 (Box 1)
    - Duckberg Times, Number 22, 1986 (Box 5)
    - Final Update (Box 1)
    - Final Update (Box 1)
    - Metrozine Number 3 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Metrozine, Number 4 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
    - New Ears Issue (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - State of the Union (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Thrillseeker [Number 3] (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Truly Needy Number 9 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Visual Lunacy Society News, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - WDC Period Number 5, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - WDC Period, Number 6, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - WDC Period, Number 7, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - WDC Period, Number 8, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - WDC Period, Number 9, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - WDC Period, Number 10, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - WDC Period, Number 11, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - WDC Period, Number 12, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - WDC Period, Number 13, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - WDC Period Number 16 (Box 5)
    - Yet Another Unslanted Opinion Number 1 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Yet Another Unslanted Opinion Number 2 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Yet Another Unslanted Opinion Number 5, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Yet Another Unslanted Opinion (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Sub-Series 2: Non D.C. Area
    - Anti-Isolation Number 3/4, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Avant-Garde World 12 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Bang!, Number 10 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Beatniks from Space, Number 5, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Between the Lines, Number 5, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Between the Lines, Number 5 1/2, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Between the Lones, Number 6, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Boris, Number 1, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Brag of the Female SubGenius (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Bravear, v. 3, Number 5, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Breaking Chains 4 Emily, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Bull Shit Monthly, Number 13 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Catalyst Konica 15 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Circular, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Circular, Number 4, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Circular, Number 5, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Circular, Number 7, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Circular, Number 8, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Circular, Number 9, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Circular, Number 10 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Circular, Number 12, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Disapproved Theories, v. 1, Number 1, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Factsheet Five, Number 19 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - False Positive, Number 5, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - False Positive, Number 6, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - False Positive Number 7 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - False Positive Number 8 (Kook ll), 1986 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Famous Hardcore of Punkland (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Famous Hardcore of Punkland (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Feminist Baseball, Number 1, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Flipside!, Number 44 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Flipside!, Number 47 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Forced Exposure, Number 10, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Hangman (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Heathen Science Monitor, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Heathen Science Monitor, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Heathen Science Monitor, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - House United Against Itself, v. 4, Number 6 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - How I Spent My Vacation (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Incoherent House, Number 5 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Incoherent House, Number 6 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Inside Joke, Number 45 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Instead of a Magazine, v. 6, Number 39 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Jersey Beat, Number24, Number V, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Leading Edge, Number 5 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Left Souls (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Live From the Stagger Cafe, Street Edition, Number 2.5 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Live From the Stagger Cafe, Number 3, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Live From the Stagger Cafe, Number 4, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Lookout, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Lookout, Number 21, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Lookout!, Number 22, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Lookout!, Number 23, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Lookout!, Number 25, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Lookout! Extra, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Lookout!, Number 26, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Lookout! Number 28, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Lookout!, Number 29, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Maximum RocknRoll, Number 12, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Myawe (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - National Photostatic Magazine v. 5, Number 27, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - ND Number 8, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Nightmares of Reason, Number 9, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Nowhere (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - No Worries, Number 5, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Not Politically Correct, Number 2 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Not Politically Correct, Number 3 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Phosphorusflourish, Number 19, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Phosphorusflourish, Number 20 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - PIAB (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Popular Reality Number 14, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Popular Reality Number 16, 1986-12-1987-01 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Popular Reality Number 17, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Popular Reality Number 18, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Pup (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Raunch-o-Rama Number 8 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Raunch-o-Rama Number 9 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Raunch-o-Rama Number 10 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Raunch-o-Rama, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Regression Number 10, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Rubber Fanzine, v. 1, Number 4, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Ruin It, Number 1, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Scrap Number 3 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Scrap Number 4 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Shoe Polish Week, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Shoot Number 14, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Sporadic Droolings (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Third Rail Number 15, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Torch of Liberty (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Troubled Times Number 6 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Twisted Image Number 6, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Untitled (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Up From Punk, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Wire, v. 4, Number 2, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - XXX Number 12 (Box 4, Folder 28)